Inventory of the Papers of Frederick D. G. Ribble 1920-1965
University of Virginia, Arthur J. Morris Law Library
- Series II (Box 14-31)
  - Restoration of the East Lawn Gardens: Correspondence, Clippings, Booklet prepared for presentation 1960-1965 (Box 24)
  - Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights under Law: Correspondence 1963-1965 (Box 24)
  - Legal Clinics and Professional Responsibility: Correspondence, Reports, Printed Matter 1962-1963 (Box 24)
  - Litigation of Interest: Correspondence, petition, briefs 1964-1965 (Box 24)
  - Carl McFarland -- Plan for Education for Government Service: Correspondence, Proposal 1965 (Box 24)
  - Miscellany: Unrelated and unidentifiable correspondence and printed matter 1932-1963; n.d. (Box 24)
  - Military Chaplains' Association of the U.S.: Correspondence 1965 (Box 25)
  - University of Missouri Lectures: Correspondence 1963-1965 (Box 25)
  - National Commission on Accrediting: Correspondence 1961-1963 (Box 25)
  - Office Supplies: Correspondence 1964 (Box 25)
  - Oklahoma [See also "Buffalo Bill" case]: Correspondence, Documents 1953-1955 (Box 25)
  - Pamphlets -- General 1891-1962 (Box 25)
  - Presidential Inauguration Official Program 1965 (Box 25)
  - Prince Edward Free School Association (PEFSA): General Correspondence with Robert P. Daniel, Colgate Darden, Jr., Thomas Henderson, Earl H. McClenny, William vanden Heuvel, Neil V. Sullivan, among others (3 folders) 1963-1965 (Box 25)
  - PEFSA: Correspondence and lists re contributions (2 folders) 1963-1964 (Box 25)
  - PEFSA: Minutes of the Board of Trustees 1963 (Box 26)
  - PEFSA -- Corporate: Correspondence and Documents re Formation of the Association 1963 (Box 26)
  - PEFSA: Speeches, Articles, etc. re Free School and related issues, by FDGR and others 1963-1964 (Box 26)
  - PEFSA: Reports from Superintendent Sullivan and others (2 folders) 1963-1964 (Box 26)
  - PEFSA: Sullivan Statement in Oakland; research material 1964 (Box 26)
  - PEFSA: Contract and other papers re Superintenden Sullivant 1963 (Box 26)
  - PEFSA: Miscellaneous Reports, Proposals, etc. (2 folders) 1963 (Box 26)
  - PEFSA: Newsclippings (2 folders) 1963-1964 (Box 27)
  - PEFSA: Yearbook for R. R. Moton High School presented to FDGR 1964 (Box 27)
  - Professional Ethics Seminar: Papers, Grades, Correspondence 1963-1964 (Box 27)
  - Professional Ethics Seminar Problems (6 folders) 1963-1964 (Box 27)
  - [Professional Ethics] Criminal Law and Professional Responsibility -- Seminar Material 1965 (Box 28)
  - Publications of U.Va. Faculty: Correspondence, bound essay, lists 1965-1966 (Box 27)
  - Raven Society: Correspondence 1964 (Box 28)
  - Reapportionment: Reports, plans, clippings 1964 (Box 28)
  - Religion in the Schools: Copies of statements 1962-1964 (Box 28)
  - University of Richmond -- Law Day Speech: Correspondence, drafts of speech 1965 (Box 28)
  - Ross Essay Contest of ABA: Correspondence 1964 (Box 28)
  - Senate Judiciary Committee: Staff report 1965 (Box 28)
  - Speeches: Drafts with corrections, printed articles covering topics and occasions such as constitutional law, Thomas Jefferson and John Marshallm dedication of court houses in Charlottesville and Lynchburg, and bar association and law review banquets 1950s (Box 28)
  - Speeches of George E. Allen and Seward Reese 1963 (Box 29)
  - State Remedies for Union Discrimination: Research notes, draft, clipping [1960s] (Box 29)
  - Stribling: Correspondence between FDGR and his cousin 1965 (Box 29)
  - Supreme Court: Clippings, copy of letter 1964-1965 (Box 29)
  - Supreme Court: Notebook kept by a layman and sent to FDGR in 1954 1934-1954 (Box 29)
  - UNESCO: Correspondence 1954-1960 (Box 29)
  - UNESCO: Bound notebook of material for committee work at the Conference on Freedom of Information in Geneva 1950 March 1-15 (Box 29)
  - Unidentified typd manuscripts ca. 1956-1964 (Box 29)
  - United Negro College Fund: Correspondence, reports 1962-1963 (Box 29)
  - Virginia State Bar Ideas: Correspondence, printed matter, text of trial demonstration 1955-1956 (Box 29)
  - Visa Cases -- Board of Appeals [1940s] (Box 29)
  - Voter Registration Bill (H.R. 6400): Correspondence, copies of statements, clipping 1965 (Box 29)
  - Washington and Lee: Drafts of articles and speeches. Topics include interstate commerce, segregation, and the courts (2 folders) 1956, n.d. (Box 30)
  - Fred Wallace Case: Correspondence, copies of documents (3 folders) 1963-1965 (Box 30)
  - Ribble and his sisters at Glendale Farm [1930s], photographs (Box 31)
  - Professional Ethics Seminars [1960s], audiotapes (Box 31)
  - Tax and Constitutional Law n.d., phonodiscs (Box 31)
- Series III (Box 32)
  - United State Military Academy -- Correspondence 1949-1950 (Box 32)
  - Correspondence with Donald R. Richberg re Oklahoma Indian Tax Exemption Claim 1953 (Box 32)
  - Correspondence about speaking engagements; two printed speeches 1953-1954 (Box 32)
  - Personal Correspondence (6 folders) 1923-1960 (Box 32)
  - Personal Financial Correspondence 1951-1953 (Box 32)